(忆往昔)
(邪恶力量)
(试播集)
(编剧)
(埃里克·克莱普克)
(如今)
不
Oh, no!
怎么回事啊
Whatever could that be?
鬼
Ghost?
我们是温家双煞
Meet Winchester.
停
Cut!
玛姬  斯沃恩
Maggie, Siobhan...
你们把这当玩笑吗
...is this some kind of a joke to you?
斯沃恩  这场戏
Siobhan, this scene takes place
是发生在卡文·爱德路德
before the events of Carver Edlund's
未出版的大作《月之暗面》(S05E16)之前
unpublished masterpiece "Dark side of the moon".
所以呢
So?
你的萨姆护身符呢
Meaning, where is the Samulet?
我给摘下来了
I took it off.
总是打到我的嘴唇
It kept hitting me in the lips, and...
那个护身符是温家兄弟的亲情象征
That amulet is a symbol of the Winchesters' brotherly love.
你得为大家忍忍
You need to take one for the team.
我只是为了大学学分才来的
Look, I'm just here for the college credit.
你好大胆
How dare you!
行了
People!
你们够了
我已经忍了这破剧三周了
Okay, I have had three weeks of this crap show,
我受够了
and I am done.
戏剧部也太戏剧化了
There is too much drama in the drama department.
我明早去找萨拉查校长
I'm going to principal Salazar in the morning.
不不不  钱德勒老师
No, no, no, no, no, no, Mrs. Chandler,
-结束了  玛丽 - 别这样
- It's over, Marie. - please...
好了  我们重新开始
All right, everybody back to one!
除非我们真被叫停  演出要继续
Until we are all suspended, the show must go on.
他们为什么不能像普通的小讨厌鬼那样
Why couldn't they just do "Godspell,"
演《摇滚福音》呢
like good little skanks?
却非得演这么个天马行空的烂恐怖故事
Instead, it's this awful, unbelievable horror story.
那种事哪里会有啊
Like that stuff really happens.
戏剧应该表现生活
Theater is about life, you know?
真理  事实
Truth... truth!
《凶鬼恶灵》有什么真实可言啊
Where is the truth in "Supernatural"?
放开  放开
Oh, get it off! Get it off!
(凶鬼恶灵)
接近了  但还是...
I mean, it's close, but it just...
还需要点...
It needs a little more, eh...
[邪恶力量 第10季第5集]
你起来多久了
How long you been up?
够长了  还给咱们找到件案子
Long enough to find us a case.
真的
Long enough to...
那么你现在都恢复正常了吗
I take it that means you're feeling back to normal?
对我们来说算是正常了吧
Yeah, whatever normal is in our world.
那个
So, uh...
看这里
Right here.
密歇根州  弗林特一个女校老师失踪了
A teacher at an all-girls school went missing in Flint, Michigan.
她当时正要去取车  就消失不见了
She was, uh, headed to her car and then disappeared.
再没人见到过她
Nobody's seen her since.
(老师失踪)
迪恩  这里面毫无有古怪的迹象
Dean, there's nothing here to even remotely suggest there's a case.
这里面也没有迹象表明  就绝对没有古怪
There is nothing there that even remotely suggests there isn't a case.
搞定
Boom.
得了  伙计
Come on, man.
萨姆  去猎魔
Sam, out there hunting...
那是我唯一的正常
That's the only normal I know.
我们要去干活儿了
We got work to do.
好的
Oh, of course.
感谢
Yes, I certainly appreciate it.
好的  谢谢  长官
You got it. Thanks, officer.
最后有人见到钱德勒老师
So, the last place Mrs. Chandler was seen by anyone
是在礼堂
was in the auditorium.
她是戏剧部的老师
Turns out she's the drama teacher.
玩戏剧的孩子  这可好
Theater kids... great.
-我就演过戏剧呢 -少来了
- I was a theater kid. - Barely.
你演了《我们小镇》  虽说不错
You did "our town," which was cool,
但后来你又去演那个破音乐剧
but then you did that crappy musical.
《俄克拉荷马》吗
That... "Oklahoma"?
休·杰克曼还演过呢
Hugh Jackman got cast off "Oklahoma""
你是负责舞台布景的  金刚狼
You ran tech, wolverine.
讨厌
Shut up.
(音乐剧  仅此一夜)
二位如果还需要什么  尽管说
If you gentlemen need anything else, just let me know.
好的  谢谢萨拉查老师
Great. Thanks, Mrs. Salazar.
白痴
Idjits.
你们这些白痴
Ya idjits.
你们就是白痴
You are idjits.
混球
Hey, assbutt!
∮ 约翰  玛丽  是一对夫妻 ∮
∮ John and Mary, husband and wife. ∮
∮ 将新生儿子带回家 ∮
∮ Bringing home a brand-new life. ∮
∮ 他名叫萨姆 ∮
∮ His name is Sammy. ∮
∮ 我是哥哥迪恩 ∮
∮ I'm big brother Dean. ∮
∮ 看似美满家庭  可现实却非如此 ∮
∮ The perfect family Or so it seemed. ∮
∮ 恶魔已然开始造访 ∮
∮ The demon's visits had begun. ∮
∮ 它认定萨姆是选定之人 ∮
∮ It believed Sam was the chosen one. ∮
∮ 它烧死了妈妈 ∮
∮ It burned my mother. ∮
∮ 还诅咒了弟弟 ∮
∮ And it cursed my brother. ∮
∮ 让我们伤心欲绝 ∮
∮ Leaving us in tears. ∮
∮ 走过的路 ∮
∮ On the road so far. ∮
∮ Yeah, the road so far. ∮
- ∮ 我们驾驶着爸爸的车 ∮  -停
- ∮ We are in dad's car... ∮ - Cut!
去跟灯光部说一下
All right, go talk to the lighting department real quick,
然后我们跟斯沃恩谈谈
and then we're gonna go talk to Siobhan.
-搞什么...  -如果有案子
- What in the h-holy... - If there is a case...
大概跟这个有关
Probably has something to do with all this.
还用说
Ya think?
-行吗  好的  -是出版商吗
- Okay? Good. - Publisher?
嗯
Yeah.
-玛姬  玛丽真是没完没了  -是啊
- Maggie, Marie just never stops. - I know.
你很棒
You were great.
天呐  你们是出版社的吗
Oh, my gosh, a-a-are you guys from the publisher?
我是玛丽  编剧/导演
I'm... I'm Marie, the writer/director.
这是梅芙  舞台监督  那是...
This is Maeve, my stage manager, and that was just a dr--
我是特别探员史密斯
I'm, uh, Special Agent Smith.
这位是我搭档
This is my partner, Special Agent...
-史密斯  -也是史密斯
- Smith. - Smith.
我们不是亲属
No relation.
我们是来调查...
W-we're here to look into the disappearance...
《凶灵恶鬼》怎么还唱上了
There is no singing in "Supernatural."
这是玛丽的演绎版本
Well, this is Marie's interpretation.
如果要唱歌
Well...I mean, if there was singing, you know...
这可能性可不大
and that's a big "if"...
即使要唱歌  也该是经典摇滚
If there was singing, it would be classic rock,
不会是安德鲁·佛洛依德·韦伯风(音乐剧演员)的
not this... Andrew Floyd Webber crap!
-是安德鲁·洛伊德·韦伯  -什么
- Andrew Lloyd Webber. - S-- what?
我们第二幕有安排
Well, you know, we do sing a cover
唱《前行吧  不羁之子》
of "Carry on Wayward Son" in the second act.
不是吧
Really?
-多经典啊  -多经典啊
- It's a classic. - It's a classic.
嗯  总之
Right. Anyways,
我们是为钱德勒老师的失踪而来
w-we're here to talk about the disappearance of Mrs. Chandler.
她失踪之前  你们见过她吗
Any chance you two saw her before she vanished?
是的
Um, yeah.
她什么时候走的  9点半左右吧
She left around like, what, 9:30?
知道她那时候会去哪里吗
Any idea where she would be headed that time of night?
酒吧
A bar.
或者贩酒店
Or a liquor store.
或者都去
Both.
这样啊
Really?
她去年离婚了  闹得很凶
She had a nasty divorce last year.
她大部分时间都沉溺于...大人果汁
Most of the time, she's sipping on her, uh... grown-up juice
要么就不省人事  一般是先喝后醉
or passed out... usually in that order.
我可不怪她
Yeah, well, I don't blame her.
我要喝50杯果冻酒  外加拿水管使劲冲澡
I'm gonna need 50 jello shots and a hose-down
才能把这洗掉
to get this stink off me.
梅芙  来检查下灯光
Maeve, we need you to check the lights.
梅芙  是吧  你是舞台监督
Maeve, right? You're the stage manager?
我还是乔迪·米尔斯的替角
And I understudy Jody Mills.
-什么  -很好  很不错
- What? - That's great. That's great.
乔迪·米尔斯  多棒啊
Jody Mills... that's great.
那不如你带我去后台转转
So, how about you give me a, uh, behind-the-scenes tour
你们导演带我搭档去钱德勒老师的办公室吧
while your director shows my partner Mrs. Chandler's office?
行吗
Deal?
好的  稍等我们一下
Great. Give us a moment, please.
好的
Okay.
我要吐了
I'm gonna throw up.
其实  也挺不错的
I mean, I got to say, it's kind of charming...
制作水准和...
t-the production value and the...
不吗  当然不
No? N-- no.
我去查电磁干扰
I'm gonna check for EMF.
你去找...诅咒物体
You... you look for, uh, cursed objects.
这些东西你们都哪来的
Where the hell did you get all this stuff?
有些是自制的  有些改造的
Some parts homemade, some parts repurposed,
都很...棒极了
all of it...awesome.
别
D-don't...
请别乱动
Please don't.
他们干什么呢
What are they doing?
他们在排练倾肠戏
Oh, uh, they are rehearsing the B.M. scene.
清肠戏啊
The bowel-movement scene?
什么啊
No!
倾诉衷肠戏
No, the boy melodrama scene.
就是他俩在一起
You know, the scene where the boys get together
一起开车  或一起靠着宝贝车
and they're... they're driving or leaning against baby,
喝喝啤酒  谈谈感受
drinking a beer, sharing their feelings.
就他们俩  虽然孤独  但拥有彼此
The two of them... alone but together.
心灵相通  兄弟联手
Bonded, united.
他们痛苦的力量...
The power of their pain is...
他们为什么站得那么近
Why are they standing so close together?
有原因啊
Reasons.
你知道他们是亲兄弟吧
You know they're brothers, right?
当然了
Well, duh.
但  可以暗示嘛
But...subtext.
我说你们往后退退吧  姑娘们
Why don't you take a substep back there, ladies?
整个排练期间  你注意到什么异常了吗
Now, have you noticed anything strange during the production?
比如  奇怪的声音
I mean... any odd noises or...
你是指这种吗
You mean something like this?
或者这个
Or perhaps this?
嗯  当然了
Right. Of course.
这个呢
How about this?
我懂了  谢谢
I-I-I got it. Thanks.
我当初在学校剧负责舞台布景时
You know, back when I did tech in school,
我们只有两个CD机
we had two cd decks.
抱歉
Oh, sorry.
我得去签收快递
I have to go sign for delivery.
请不要碰任何东西
Please don't touch anything.
抱歉
Sorry.
(戏剧是生活)
这是她的
This hers?
不是
No.
那是第二幕的道具
That's a prop from act 2.
我还一直在找呢
I've been looking for that, actually.
《凶灵恶鬼》里面没有太空元素啊
There's no space in "Supernatural".
原著是没有
Well, not canonically, no,
但这是改编版的
but this is transformative fiction.
同人小说吧
You mean fan fiction.
随你怎么说吧
Call it whatever you like, okay?
是受卡文·爱德路德小说启发
It's inspired by Carver Edlund's books...
并做了适当修饰
with a few embellishments.
你也知道  恰克在《最后一战》(S05E22)之后就封笔了
Well, as you know, Chuck stopped writing after "Swan Song".
我不能让故事就那么结束啊
I just I couldn't leave it the way that it was.
迪恩不再猎魔了
I mean, Dean not hunting anymore,
搬去跟莉莎住
living with Lisa,
萨姆从地狱回来了  却不去找迪恩
S-Sam somehow back from hell but not with Dean?
所以我写了自己的结局
So, um, I wrote my own ending.
你自己写了结局  还加入了...
You wrote your own ending... with...
太空船吗
Spaceships?
还有机器人  忍者
And robots and some ninjas.
然后迪恩变成了女人
And then Dean becomes a woman.
就是几场戏
It-- it's just for a few scenes.
听着  大文豪  我其实可以告诉你
All right, Shakespeare, you know that I can actually tell you
萨姆和迪恩后来的情况
what really happened with, uh, Sam and Dean.
有个朋友帮我拿到了
A friend of mine hooked me up with the, uh...
未出版的书
Unpublished unpublished books.
萨姆从地狱回来了  但却没带回来灵魂
So, Sam came back from hell, but without his soul.
然后小卡从炼狱里带回来一群利维坦
Then Cass brought in a bunch of Leviathans from purgatory.
鲍比死了
Uh, they lost Bobby.
然后小卡和迪恩还困在炼狱里了
And then Cass and Dean got stuck in purgatory.
萨姆撞了狗
Sam hit a dog.
他们遇到一个叫凯文的先知
Uh, they met a prophet named Kevin.
然后他也死了
They lost him, too.
然后萨姆去进行了一系列测试
Then Sam underwent a series of trials...
以试图关上地狱大门
in an attempt to close the gates of hell...
而这几乎让他送命
Which... nearly cost him his life.
而迪恩呢...变成了恶魔
And Dean... well, Dean became a demon.
地狱骑士
A knight of hell, actually.
是啊
Yep.
简直是我听过的最狗血的同人小说了
That is some of the worst fan fiction that I have ever heard!
拜托啊
I mean, seriously, though, no,
你朋友上哪找到这种破烂的
where'd your friend find this garbage?
我们的虽然不是杰作
I-I'm not saying that ours is a masterpiece or anything,
但是  天呐
but geez.
我回头给你发点同人小说链接
I'll have to send you some fic-links later.
他们在干什么
What are they doing?
如今的孩子管那叫"抱抱"
Kids these days call it "Hugging."
这也是节目一部分吗
Is that in the show?
不是的
Oh. No.
斯沃恩和克里斯汀真是一对
Siobhan and Kristen are a couple in real life.
不过我们第二幕的确有探讨"迪卡"的关系
Although, we do explore the nature of Destiel in act 2.
什么
Sorry... what?
就是暗示啦
Oh, it's just subtext.
不过嘛
But, then again, you know,
暗示当然是
you can't spell "subtex" without...
性方面的
s-e-x.
我真搞不懂
I don't understand.
我也是
Me neither.
应该是叫"迪西迪奥"吧
I mean, shouldn't it be "Dea-stiel"?
不是吧  这就是你的吐槽点吗
Really? That's your issue with this?
当然不是了
No, of course it's not my issue.
话说  "萨卡"  "萨西迪奥"怎么样
You know, how about... "Sastiel," "Samstiel"?
行了  我告诉你  你要这么做
Okay, all right, you know what? You're gonna do that thing
给我闭嘴  永远别说话了
where you just shut the hell up... forever.
伙计  没有电磁干扰  没有巫术袋
Look, man, no EMF, no hex bags.
他们的道具也都没有问题
None of their props are even remotely hinky.
除了剧情天马行空  我没查到别的了
Other than the Charlie Kaufman of it all, I got nothing.
你呢
You?
钱德勒老师办公室里
No, miss Chandler's office
只有空酒瓶和一堆后悔
was just a pile of empty bottles and regret.
她大概醉倒在哪个酒吧  或水沟里了
She's probably facedown in a bar somewhere or a ditch.
好吧  那么这件事
All right, so, what, this... this whole...
这个音乐剧
This whole musical thing, everything, it's just...
就只是巧合吗
It's all a coincidence?
根本没有古怪
There is no case?
除非你看到了我漏掉的线索
Unless you're seeing something I'm not,
否则  迪恩  这里没有古怪
no, Dean, there's no case here.
好吧
Okay.
"卡西迪恩"呢
"CasDean"?
给我闭嘴  进车里
Shut your face. Get in the car.
玛姬  别这样
Maggie! Come on!
别这样
J-- please don't do this.
其他人都愿意遵从你的独裁
Everyone else is willing to follow your little dictatorship,
但我不会
but not me.
我一直在跟你说  玛丽
I've been telling you all along, Marie...
如果不是原著上的  就不该写进戏里
If it's not canon, then it shouldn't be in the show.
我们就该按我说的  排演《局外人》
You know, we should've just done "The outsiders," like I told you.
别这样
Just...
回来嘛  我们好商量
Come back inside. We can make this work.
我明早去找萨拉查校长
I'm going to principal Salazar's in the morning.
我要做钱德勒老师醉得没做到的事
Gonna do what Mrs. Chandler was too drunk to finish.
这可好
Great.
玛姬
Maggie?
Maggie!
我问过校长了
So, checked with the principal.
监控录像上毫无结果
There's nothing on the surveillance tapes.
警察怎么看
What the cops think?
他们唯一找到的线索在垃圾桶旁边
You know, the only clue they found was by the dumpster.
他们在钱德勒老师的手机旁找到了一样的花
They found the Same flower near Mrs. Chandler's cellphone.
-认得吗  -不
- You recognize it? - No.
我也是
Yeah, me neither.
我给你泡了茶
I made you some tea.
我猜猜
Let me guess.
你们也是来取笑我的吗
You guys came here to laugh at me, too, right?
跟我们说说你的朋友到底出了什么事
Why don't you tell us what happened to your friend?
玛姬辞演了
Maggie quit the show.
她想阻止我们继续排演
She was trying to get us shut down,
我们就吵了起来
and so we were fighting.
然后她就走了  我听到了她的尖叫声
The she left and I heard her scream.
我就跑出去帮忙
So I ran outside to help.
结果
And...
却看到一个稻草人
And I saw a scarecrow.
看上去跟我们剧里的那个一样
It looked just like the one from our show, but...
但是是活的
alive.
然后呢
Then what?
它用藤蔓捆住了她
I-it wrapped her up in vines
然后把她拖到垃圾箱后面去了
a-and took her behind a dumpster.
然后他们都消失不见了
And then they were both just...gone.
于是我报了警  一群大人说
So, I called the cops, and a bunch of adults
我只是想象力太丰富了
just told me I had an overactive imagination.
但都是真的
But it's all real.
鬼魂  天使  恶魔
Ghosts, angels... demons.
我也想相信
I want to believe.
你应该相信
You should believe.
你们都该相信  那都是真的
You both should 'cause it is all real.
我们也是
And so are we.
我是萨姆·温彻斯特
I'm Sam Winchester.
这是迪恩
That's Dean.
好吧
Okay.
听着
Now, look.
我愿意接受怪物是真的
I'm willing to accept that monsters are real,
但《凶灵恶鬼》只是小说而已
but those books... are works of fiction.
而且你们太老了  不可能是萨姆和迪恩
And you guys are way too old to be Sam or Dean.
是啊
Oh, yeah.
我看你们更像鲁弗斯和鲍比
More of a Rufus/Bobby combo... maybe.
好吧  阳光小美女
Okay, all right, little miss sunshine.
我们是书里所说的猎人
We are what the books call hunters.
联调局的猎人吗
FBI hunters?
是的
Yeah.
你们是《X档案》
You guys are "X-files."
嗯  行啊  可以这么说
Sure. Yeah. You could say that.
你音乐剧用到的稻草人
So, the scarecrow in your musical...
是根据书里改编的吗
Is it based on the one from the books?
不是的  我改了
No. I changed it.
我小时候特别怕当地的一个传说
I got scared of a local legend when I was a kid.
镇外一座废弃的农场
There was this old, creepy scarecrow
有个破旧吓人的稻草人
on an abandoned farm outside of town.
孩子们会说如果被它抓到
Kids used to say if it caught you,
它就会把你带走
it would take you away.
好吧  如果这个稻草人是根据你的版本来的
Okay, if this scarecrow is based off of your version,
那钱德勒老师和玛姬就可能还活着
then miss Chandler and Maggie might still be alive.
你觉得稻草人是我们的剧创造的
You think the scarecrow was created by the play?
你觉得
You think...
是个幻象怪
It's a tulpa.
幻象怪是由强烈  专注的想法
Tulpas are monsters that are created by intense,
产生的怪物
focused energy on an idea.
或者是个故事
Or a story.
好吧  想法要怎么杀啊
Great. How do you kill an idea?
《地狱鬼宅》(S01E17)中  萨姆和迪恩烧掉了一座房子
Well, in "Hell House," Sam and Dean burned the house down...
以解决他们对付的那个幻象怪
to take out the one tulpa they hunted.
是啊  杀掉象征  就能杀掉幻象怪
Yeah, yeah, you kill the symbol, you kill the tulpa.
这是个好开端
It's, uh, actually a pretty good start.
你们剧中的稻草人  是个人还是个道具
So, the scarecrow in your play, is it a person or a prop?
道具
Prop.
很吓人的
And it's terrifying.
我们放在锅炉房了
We keep it in the boiler room.
很好
That's, uh...great.
你们继续看
Um, okay, you guys read up.
等我们一会儿
Just give us a sec.
不对啊
Yeah, so, this doesn't add up.
幻象怪需要很多的精神能量才能形成
Tulpas require a-a ton of psychic energy to juice up.
是啊
Yeah.
《凶灵恶鬼》又不是
Well, it's not like the "Supernatural" books
《纽约时报》的畅销书
are tearing up the New York Times best-seller list,
我严重怀疑这部剧有没有满座
and I seriously doubt this play is even sold out.
希望没有
Hope not.
但是呢  那个花
Oh, but you know what? This flower...
我一定在什么地方见过
I know I've seen it in the lore somewhere.
这其中肯定有联系的
There's got to be a connection.
好吧  你去查那个  我去看看火人
All right, you get on that. I'm gonna take a shot at burning man.
-嗯  -好
- Yeah. - Okay.
你能带我去锅炉房吗
Can you show me to the boiler room?
嗯
Yeah.
好啊
Sure.
做好准备
Gird your loins.
很吓人的
It's horrifying.
不是吧
Really?
是啊  吓人吧
I know. Scary, right?
你要亲手解决这混球吗
You want to piata this asshat?
混球
"Asshat"?
不错  挺像迪恩的
Nice. It's, uh, very Dean.
不用  他归你了  史密斯探员
No, he's all yours, agent Smith.
谢谢
Thank you.
我们去了  我们看到了  我们毁...
We came, we saw, we kicked...
不是幻象怪
It's not a tulpa.
什么
What?
不是幻象怪
It's not a tulpa.
再说一遍  不过更像施瓦辛格那样
Say it one more time, but just a little bit more Arnold,
这样...不是幻象怪
you know, like... it's not a tulpa.
行了
Dude, come on.
-是卡利奥佩  -谁
- It's Calliope. - Who?
史诗女神  缪斯
The goddess of epic poetry... the muse.
她跟这个有关  玻璃苣
She's associated with this... the borage or starflower.
就是这个
That's the picture.
等等  如果是跟神有关
Okay, wait... if this is a god thing,
那稻草人是闹哪样
then what's with the scarecrow?
据传说  卡利奥佩会根据
According to the lore, Calliope manifests creatures
自己喜欢的故事创造怪物
from the stories she's tuned into.
那么说  稻草人还活着
So...the scarecrow is still alive
而我们无缘无故烧了我的道具
and we burned my prop for nothing?
那东西就该烧掉
Oh, that thing needed to burn.
想要毁掉稻草人  就得杀掉卡利奥佩
The only way to destroy the scarecrow is to kill Calliope.
嗯  她会利用自己创造的东西  比如稻草人
Right... she uses these manifestations, like the scarecrow,
来激励作者  并保护他们
to inspire the author and protect them
直到他们的愿景实现
until their vision is realized.
然后呢
Then what?
然后她吃掉作者
Then she eats the author.
太糟了
Okay, that's bad.
你们如愿了
Well... you get your wish.
我们取消音乐剧吧
Let's cancel the show.
你的老师和同学都是这么干的
That's what your teacher and classmate did.
他们想阻止剧目上演
They tried to shut you down,
稻草人绑走了他们
and the scarecrow took them...
是为了保护你和你的剧
Protected you and the show.
那么稻草人是个妖怪
Okay, so, the scarecrow is a boogeyman.
我们得去找这个
We got to take our shot with this, uh...
-卡利奥佩  -卡利奥佩
- Calliope. - ...Calliope.
但想要看到她  得先让...
But she won't show herself until...
你的愿景实现
Your vision is realized.
那么
So...
你什么意思
What are you saying?
演出必须继续
The show must go on.
我去...
Hey, uh, why don't I...
你们给玛丽鼓鼓劲
Why don't you guys rally Marie?
我去车厢里找些木桩来
I'm gonna grab some wooden stakes from the trunk
然后进行祈福
and do the blessing.
玛丽会被吃吗
Is Marie gonna get eaten?
不会的
Not gonna happen.
大幕一拉开
Soon as that curtain rises,
我们就会去干掉卡利奥佩
we are gonna be there to take out this Calliope.
你怎么样了  丫头
How you doing, champ?
这
This...
这都怪我
This is all my fault.
如果不是我写了这部破剧
If I hadn't written this dumb play,
就不会发生这种事了
none of this would've happened.
首先  这部剧不破
Okay, well, first of all, uh, the play's not dumb.
你不是不喜欢她的版本吗
I thought you didn't believe in this interpretation.
我是不喜欢
I don't.
一点也不喜欢
Like at all.
但是你喜欢
B-but you do, okay?
我需要你全心全意地投入进去
And I need you to believe in it with all you got
这样我们就能杀了卡利奥佩  救出你的朋友
so that we can kill Calliope and we can save your friends.
你能做到吗
Can you do that?
嗯  你说得对
Yeah. You're right.
如果萨姆和迪恩是真的
If Sam and Dean were real...
他们也不会退缩
They wouldn't back down from a fight.
尤其是我可爱  勇敢  无私的萨姆
Especially my sweet... brave...selfless Sam.
他无所不能
There's nothing he can't do.
得了
No.
好吧
Okay.
就这么干吧
Let's do this.
我是萨姆的替角  所以...
I understudy Sam, so...
我去年演独角戏《黑色孤儿》时用了这个
I used this for my one-woman "Orphan Black" show last year.
只能用这个扮萨姆了
But it's gonna have to work for Sam.
编剧
Writer.
导演
Director.
演员
Actor.
我要像芭芭拉·史翠珊一样演得出彩
I'm gonna barbra streisand this bitch.
(兄弟之情能否战胜邪恶的黑暗力量)
好了
Okay.
很好
Good.
很好  不错
Good. Okay.
很好
Good.
等等
Wait.
完美
Perfect.
好了  萨姆护身符呢
Okay, samulet?
萨姆护身符
The...samulet?
那个护身符是温家兄弟之情的标志
That amulet is a symbol of the Winchesters' brotherly love.
我太激动了
So excited.
好的  很好  很好
Okay, good. Good.
嗯
Yeah.
摆好姿势  站直了
Posture. Straighten up.
好了
Okay.
挺好的
Pretty good.
等等  恰克去哪里了
Wait a second. Where's Chuck?
我很喜欢他的
Oh, I-I-I love him. I do.
但是  说实话
But, honestly,
"作者将自身投入叙事之中"的这种桥段
the whole "author inserting themselves into the narrative" thing,
我不是很喜欢
it's just not my favorite.
我蛮讨厌元小说的
I kind of hate the meta stories.
-我也是  -我也是
- Me too. - Me too.
好了  听好了  姑娘们
All right, listen up, girls,
我知道你们来演剧
now, I know you're all here
是因为你都喜欢《凶鬼恶灵》
because you love "Supernatural"
实际上  我本希望我们能演《女巫前传》
Actually, I was hoping we'd do "wicked."
是啊  那就没这么多麻烦了
Yeah, that'd have been easier.
我知道关于这个特别版的《凶鬼恶灵》
Uh, I know I have expressed some differences of opinion
我表达了一些不同的意见
regarding this particular version of "Supernatural,"
但是今晚
Uh, but tonight...
要演出玛丽的版本
it is all about Marie's vision.
这是玛丽的《凶鬼恶灵》
This is Marie's "Supernatural."
所以我希望你们上台去
So I want you to get out there,
尽可能按她设想的那样表演
and I want you to stand as close as she wants you to,
饱含感情地去念台词
and I want you to put as much sub into that text
把暗示都念出来
as you possibly can.
没有其他的路可走
There is no other road,
没有其他的方式
no other way,
没有别的机会...
no day...
只有今日一搏
but today.
他刚刚是引用了《吉屋出租》吗
Did he just quote "Rent"?
不至于给我们惹麻烦
Not enough to get us in trouble.
你们站到台前  去大放光彩吧
Now, you get out there and you kick it in the ass.
好了  来走一个
All right, bring it in!
抓鬼
Ghost...
特工队
Facers.
晚上好  各位
Good evening, everybody.
欢迎来观赏我们的演出  《凶鬼恶灵》
Uh, welcome to our production of "Supernatural."
不骗你们  部分内容
Not gonna lie -- it might be a full-on Gallagher show
会很有笑点
up in this piece.
坐在前排的观众们
Um, so those of you in the front rows
可能会要用到我们提供的雨衣
may want to use the ponchos we've provided for you
就在座位下面
under your seats.
你们可能会在观剧过程中被打湿
You may, in fact, get wet on this ride.
我想要谢谢
Um, I would -- I would like to thank
剧组成员...
the, uh, cast and the crew for...
好了  她在拖延时间  我们动手吧
Okay, she's stalling. Let's do this.
收到
Copy that.
幕布  孩子们  演出时间到了
Curtain, kids. It's showtime.
-我想要感谢...  -幕布准备好了
- Um, I'd like to thank - Curtain ready.
开启音效  开始
Roll sound. Go.
好吧  那么...
Okay, um, and... and...
接下来  便是今晚的演出
A-and that concludes our introduction for the night,
大家都坐好
so everybody just sit back,
放松  享受演出吧
relax, and enjoy the show.
所有人就位
Everyone in places.
∮ 约翰  玛丽  是一对夫妻 ∮
∮ John and Mary, husband and wife. ∮
∮ 将新生儿子带回家 ∮
∮ Bringing home a brand-new life. ∮
∮ 他名叫萨姆 ∮
∮ His name is Sammy. ∮
∮ 我是哥哥迪恩 ∮
∮ I'm big brother Dean. ∮
∮ 看似美满家庭  可现实却非如此 ∮
∮ The perfect family Or so it seemed. ∮
∮ 恶魔已然开始造访 ∮
∮ The demon's visits had begun. ∮
∮ 它认定萨姆是选定之人 ∮
∮ It believed Sam was the chosen one. ∮
∮ 它烧死了妈妈 ∮
∮ It burned my mother. ∮
∮ 还诅咒了弟弟 ∮
∮ And it cursed my brother. ∮
∮ 让我们伤心欲绝 ∮
∮ Leaving us in tears. ∮
∮ 走过的路 ∮
∮ On the road so far. ∮
∮ Yeah, the road so far. ∮
∮ 我们驾驶着爸爸的车 ∮
∮ We are in dad's car... ∮
-看身后  - ∮ 走过这一路 ∮
- Turn around! - ∮ On the road so far. ∮
∮ 爸爸心意决然  不会放弃 ∮
∮ Dad was driven, no turning back. ∮
∮ 不报此仇  誓不罢休 ∮
∮ He wouldn't stop without the payback. ∮
∮ 他训练我们 ∮
∮ He trained us both to. ∮
∮ 追踪  抓捕和杀戮 ∮
∮ track and hunt and kill. ∮
∮ 他夺走了我们自己的意愿 ∮
∮ He took away our own free will. ∮
∮ 于是成了今天这样 ∮
∮ so that's where we are. ∮
∮ 走过的路 ∮
∮ On the road so far. ∮
∮ 拯救生命 ∮
∮ Saving people. ∮
∮ 斩妖除魔 ∮
∮ Hunting things. ∮
∮ 家族事业 ∮
∮ Family business. ∮
∮ 东山再起 ∮
∮ Back in swing. ∮
∮ 一路走来至今 ∮
∮ Driving down the road so far. ∮
准备  5  4  3  2  上
Ready in 5...4...3...2... Go.
史密斯探员
Agent Smith?
我们在哪
Where the hell are we?
学校地下室  稻草人把我们弄下来的
School's basement. The scarecrow brought us down here.
我几天前就试过了
Yeah, I tried that days ago.
怎么  我们被困在这里了吗
So, what? We're stuck in here?
没错
That's right.
你们要错过大戏了
You're gonna miss the big show.
好吧  你可以明早过来
Okay, so, you can pop in tomorrow morning.
好
Yes.
我会...
I'll just...
在这里等着
...wait here, then.
我们现在怎么办
So, what do we do now?
照计划行事  明白吗
Just stick to the plan, okay?
继续唱  直到稻草人来抓你
Keep singing until the scarecrow comes for you.
∮ 我就这么做 ∮
∮ That's what I'll do. ∮
∮ 我会在这里等待 ∮
∮ I'll just wait here, then. ∮
∮ 等待我上场 ∮
∮ Wait for my cue. ∮
∮ 我将你救出地狱 ∮
∮ I raised you from perdition. ∮
∮ 作为上帝的武器 ∮
∮ to be God's ammunition. ∮
∮ 可现在你需要休息 ∮
∮ But now you need some rest. ∮
∮ 我还是顾全大局 ∮
∮ so I will do what's best. ∮
∮ 在这里等着就好 ∮
∮ and just wait here, then. ∮
∮ 我就这么做 ∮
∮ That's all I'll do. ∮
∮ 我会在这里等待 ∮
∮ I'll just wait here, then. ∮
∮ 等着你 ∮
∮ I'll wait for you. ∮
我吞噬过很多作家  很多故事
I've consumed many authors, many stories.
可今晚
But tonight...
幕布一拉开
as soon as that curtain opened,
我就知道这故事有点特别
I knew something special was brewing with this one.
或许是因为故事中的原型就在现场
Maybe it's because the story's actual inspiration is here.
怎么办呢
I don't know.
看来我只能杀了你和你哥哥  找出答案了
I guess I'm just gonna have to kill you and your brother to find out.
难道你不用等到愿景实现吗
Don't you have to wait until the vision has been realized?
天呐
Oh, Gods.
如果要我再忍受一遍第二幕...
If I have to sit through that second act one more time...
竟然有机器人和宇宙怪物
There's robots and tentacles in space.
我都不敢想
I can't even.
[咒语]
∮ 男儿之泪  顺脸庞滑落 ∮
∮ A single man tear slips down his face. ∮
∮ 悄无声息  感情流露 ∮
∮ He shows emotion without a trace. ∮
∮ 躲藏在坚强的外表下 ∮
∮ He hides behind a mask so strong. ∮
∮ 担心自己可能犯下了错误 ∮
∮ Worried that he could be wrong. ∮
∮ 真希望他能知道我对他的看法 ∮
∮ I wish that he could see the way I see him. ∮
∮ 最棒的哥哥  最完美的人 ∮
∮ The perfect brother, a man without sin. ∮
∮ 因为在铁血硬汉的光辉下 ∮
∮ 'cause underneath the manly sheen. ∮
∮ 他只是我哥哥  叫迪恩的男孩 ∮
∮ It is my brother, a boy named Dean. ∮
∮ 男儿之泪 ∮
∮ A single man tear. ∮
∮ 是我们唯一的恐惧 ∮
∮ That's all we fear. ∮
[咒语]
∮ 男儿之泪  不轻弹 ∮
∮ A single man tear that's all I'll spare. ∮
好了  幻想照进现实了
Okay, we're through the looking glass here, people.
上食人怪布景  准备牧师戏服
Strike the wendigo set. Let's prep the priest costumes.
萨拉  给替角化妆做头发
And, Sarah, get our understudies into hair and makeup.
∮ 如今我被追杀 ∮
∮ Now I'm hunted. ∮
为什么选这个故事
So, why this story, huh?
为什么选  《凶鬼恶灵》
Why, uh, "Supernatural"?
《凶鬼恶灵》拥有一切
"Supernatural" has everything.
生  死
Life, death,
复活  救赎
resurrection, redemption.
木桩
The stake.
尤其是...
But above all...
拿给他
Give it to him.
家人
Family.
伴随着美妙的音乐
All set to music you can really tap your toe to.
不是那种乱侃大山的垃圾作品
It isn't some meandering piece of genre dreck.
它是部...史诗
It's... epic.
∮ 但在那破碎的面具下 ∮
∮ But underneath this broken mask. ∮
∮ 是我的父亲  他满腔愤怒 ∮
∮ It is my father, with all his wrath. ∮
而那...
And that...
就是我的最爱
well, that is my bag of tea.
尝尝这个
Bag this!
∮ 我自己 ∮
∮ ...my own man. ∮
∮ 但在那破碎的面具下 ∮
∮ But underneath this broken mask. ∮
∮ 是我的父亲  他满腔愤怒 ∮
∮ It is my father, with all his wrath. ∮
∮ 男儿之泪 ∮
∮ A single man tear. ∮
才不要哭哭啼啼的桥段
No chick-flick moments!
鞠个躬  萨姆
Take a bow, Sammy.
(幕间休息)
一般到了这时候  萨姆和迪恩
Usually, this is where Sam and Dean take off
就会趁有人来得及提问之前开溜了
before anyone asks any questions.
是个好主意
That's probably a good idea.
谢谢你们救了我的朋友
Thanks for saving my friends.
没事
Sure.
知道吗  如果你剪短头发
You know, if you cut your hair a little,
你还挺像迪恩的
you'd make a pretty good Dean.
谢谢
Thanks.
你干的很不错  丫头
Well, you did good out there, kid.
你也不差
You're not so bad yourself.
这还挺有...教育意义的
You know, this has been... educational...
从你的角度去思考这个故事
Seeing the... story from your perspective.
继续写下去  大文豪
You keep writing, Shakespeare.
尽管你不赞同吗
Even if it doesn't match how you see it?
我有我的版本  你有你的
I have my version, and you have yours.
一分钟  各位  一分钟
One minute, folks, one minute.
好了
Okay.
迪恩
Dean?
你不该把这个扔掉的
You never should've thrown this away.
这根本没起作用
It never really worked.
我不需要什么标志来提醒我
I don't need a symbol to remind me
我对弟弟的感情
how I feel about my brother, so...
拿着吧
Just take it...
混蛋
Jerk.
贱人
Bitch.
好吧
Right. Okay.
音效  汽车发动
Sound car start.
准备
Stand by.
幕布  拉开
Curtain, go.
我想我们可以回去继续瞪着旅馆房间墙壁了
I guess we can go back to staring at motel-room walls.
你知道吗  迪恩
You know what, Dean?
你没错
You were right.
傻待着对我们没有帮助
Staying cooped up isn't helping us.
-我们得...  -我们得继续上路了  迪恩
- We need -- - We need to be back on the road, Dean,
做我们最擅长的事
doing what we do best.
-那是什么  -我只是
- What is that? - I just...
我也不确定了
I don't know anymore.
倾肠戏
It's the, uh, the B.M. Scene.
-救人  猎魔  -清肠戏吗
- Saving people, hunting things. - Bowel-movement scene?
-家族事业  -嘘  不是
- You know, the family business. - Shh. No.
别出声
Just...shh.
你是对的  萨姆
You're right, Sammy.
上路
Out on the road...
只有我们俩
Just the two of us.
我们俩  面对全世界
The two of us against the world.
正如她所说
What she said.
∮ 前行吧  我不羁的孩子 ∮
∮ Carry on, my wayward son. ∮
∮ 你们最终会找到安宁 ∮
∮ There'll be peace when you are done. ∮
∮ 躺下你们疲惫的身躯 ∮
∮ Lay your weary head to rest. ∮
∮ 不要再哭泣 ∮
∮ Don't you cry no more. ∮
∮ 曾经我脱离了一切喧嚣和困惑 ∮
∮ Once I rose above the noise and confusion. ∮
∮ 只想透过幻象  一瞥现实 ∮
∮ Just to get a glimpse beyond this illusion. ∮
∮ 我本越飞越高 ∮
∮ I was soaring ever higher. ∮
那是谁
Who's that?
那是亚当  约翰·温彻斯特另一个孩子
Oh, that's Adam, John Winchester's other kid.
∮ 但却太靠近天穹 ∮
∮ But I flew too high. ∮
他还和路西法一起被关在地狱里
He's still trapped in a cage in hell with Lucifer.
∮ 装作秉承信念之人 ∮
∮ Masquerading as a man with a reason. ∮
∮ 我的伪装令人刮目 ∮
∮ My charade is the event of the season. ∮
∮ 如果我自称心如明镜 ∮
∮ And if I claim to be a wise man. ∮
∮ 那我一定内心迷惘 ∮
∮ It surely means I don't know. ∮
∮ 前行吧  我不羁的孩子 ∮
∮ Carry on, my wayward son. ∮
∮ 你们最终会找到安宁 ∮
∮ There'll be peace when you are done. ∮
∮ 躺下你们疲惫的身躯 ∮
∮ Lay your weary head to rest. ∮
∮ 不要再哭泣 ∮
∮ Don't you cry no more. ∮
∮ 前行吧 ∮
∮ Carry on. ∮
-再见  -再见  抱歉
- Bye. - Oh. Bye. Sorry.
谢谢  谢谢
Thank you. Thank you.
你留给出版商的票  有人拿走了
The ticket you left for the publisher -- someone claimed it.
我的天
Oh, my gosh.
但是等等
But wait.
那么卡利奥佩是为我来的  还是...
Does that mean that Calliope came for me or for --
谁在乎呢  去吧  大粉丝
Who cares? Go, fangirl!
谢谢  太感谢你来了
Thank you... so much for coming.
我知道第二幕有点不靠谱
Uh, I know the second act is a little bit wonky
第一幕也有些问题
and the first act has some issues,
但是你觉得呢
But... what did you think?
不赖
Not bad.